

eduardocsilva2000@gmail.com



+351 910597715



Porto, Portugal



eduardocsilva.github.io



linkedin.com/in/eduardo-csilva



github.com/eduardocsilva

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Leadership

Teamwork

Flexibility

Proactivity

Independence

Problem Solving

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Programming

Technology

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Web Development

Reading

Music

Sports

Eduardo Silva

Informatics Engineer

An independent and proactive individual with a BSc in Informatics Engineering and currently attending a MSc in AI Engineering at ISEP, with a strong background in Software Engineering and Web Development, as well as Data Science and Machine Learning, aspiring to a professional career in Artificial Intelligence. Strong team spirit and creativity due to 9 years as a federated football player and 4 years of experience as a musician.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence Engineering

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

10/2021 - Present

- Machine Learning and Data Engineering
- □ Intelligent Environments & Multi-Agent Systems
- Planning and Decision Making

Average Grade: 19 / 20

Natural Language Processing

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

09/2018 - 07/2021 Final Average Grade: 18/20

- Software and Application Engineering
- Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures
- Data Science and Machine Learning
- Linear Algebra and Computational Mathematics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data & Al Engineer

BMW Group - Critical TechWorks

11/2021 - Present Porto, Portugal

Head of Informatics Department

Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática - ISEP

03/2021 - 09/2022 Porto, Portugal

PROJECTS

Internship Project - Automatic Contact List Cleaning System (E-goi) (03/2021 - 07/2021)

Technologies: JavaScript, Angular.js, PHP, R, Python, Jupyter, FastAPI, Scikit-learn, Pandas, MySQL, SQLite, etc. (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 5 - Public Transport Planning and Management App (09/2020 - 01/2021)

Technologies: Node.js, React/Redux, C#, .NET Core, Prolog, SQL Server, MongoDB, UML, etc. (Grade: 19 / 20)

Laboratory and Project 4 - Factory Floor Management Application (03/2020 - 07/2020)

Technologies: Java, C, JSON, XML, XSD, XSL, H2 SQL, UML (Grade: 19/20)

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera) (60 hours) (08/2020 - 11/2020)

Introduction to Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised Learning), Data Mining and Statistical Pattern Recognition

HARD SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, C

Frameworks & libraries: Scikit-learn, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, FastAPI, SQLAlchemy, React.js

Databases: MongoDB, Vertica SQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Oracle SQL, SQLite

OTHER SKILLS

Musician (10/2017 - Present)

Guitarist for 4 years, Ballroom Dancer for 2 years and Drummer for 2 years

Federated Football Player (08/2008 - 08/2017)

Goalkeeper for the clubs União Desportiva Valonguense (2008-2014) and União Desportiva Sousense (2014-2017)